Legend has it that 400 years
ago, Blaise Pascal made a bet.
传说在400年前，布莱斯·帕斯卡打了一个赌
(Blaise) "I bet I can break
this large barrel of water
(Blaise) 我打赌只要另加一升水
with the weight of just one
additional liter of water!"
我就能把这个盛水的大桶撑破
(Heckler) "How would you do that?"
(Heckler) 你会怎么做
(Blaise) "I'll pour it into a long thin tube
(Blaise) 我会把它倒进这根细长的管子里
and the tall column of water will create
enough pressure in the barrel to burst it!"
然后这管水就会在桶里产生足够的压强把它炸开
(Heckler) "How could a little
water create so much pressure?"
(Heckler) 这么一点水怎会产生那么大的压力呢？
(Blaise) "Pressure is forced over area, so
even a small force concentrated in a tiny area
(Blaise) 压强是作用在单位面积上的力 所以即使是集中在很小面积上微弱的力
can create a huge pressure. This pressure applied
at the top will squeeze the water in the barrel
也能产生很大的压强 施加在顶部的压强会挤压桶中的水
which will then push outwards with
a huge force bursting the barrel."
并形成一股强大的外推力把桶挤爆
My historical research suggests that Pascal
never actually tried bursting a barrel to test
我的历史学研究表明帕斯卡其实没有试过炸桶来测试他的理论
his hypothesis... but we can! If he's right, we
can burst even the strongest barrel with just
但是我们可以 如果他是对的 只要我们制作一根足够坚固的细长管
one liter of water, provided we build a long
thin and strong enough tube to pour it in.
我们仅需要倒进一升水就可以撑破最坚固的桶
(Blaise) "Sacre bleu, I was right!"
(Blaise) 草 我是对的